<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerala Ruby Users Group</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://krug.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://krug.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Meetup - 6 Oct, 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id='talks'&gt;Talks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garden City Rubyconf (Prakash Murthy)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Intro to Grape-Goliath (by Kannan from Qburst)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;XMPP4R (by Harisankar from Ruby Kitchen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;: Mobme Wireless, 41/3197, Fourth Floor, Bhageeratha Square, Near Town Hall, Kacheripady, Kochi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 2-5pm, 6th October, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSVP&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href='https://www.facebook.com/events/641152625924594/'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href='http://gathers.us/events/kerala-ruby-users-group-meetup-oct-2013'&gt;Gathers.us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='summary_of_the_meetup'&gt;Summary of the meetup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='talk_intro_to_grapegoliath'&gt;Talk: Intro to grape-goliath&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.slideshare.net/kannanreghu9/grape-golilath'&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://rubygems.org/gems/grape_goliath'&gt;grape_goliath on Rubygems.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/qburstruby/grape_goliath'&gt;grape_goliath on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/qburstruby?tab=repositories'&gt;Other gems from Qburst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id='talk_xmpp4r'&gt;Talk: XMPP4R&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://github.com/xmpp4r/xmpp4r'&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://xmpp4r.github.io'&gt;Web Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.slideshare.net/coderhs/xmpp4r'&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-october-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-october-2013</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meetup Minutes - 14th July, 2012</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id='quick_summary_of_the_meetup'&gt;Quick summary of the meetup:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intro to NLP - Hari gave an intro to NLP and spoke about how we can use some Ruby libraries for NLP in Ruby. He will be continuing the discussion about NLP at the next meetup when he&amp;#8217;ll talk about Treat - an NLP library for Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaprogramming Ruby - Deepak started a series of talks about metaprogramming in Ruby. He spoke about the Ruby object model. This was the first part of a series of talks he will be doing about metaprogramming and he will be doing the next part of the talk at the next meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RubyConf India 2014 - We also discussed about the possibility of hosting the next RubyConf India in Kochi. We are already in touch with the RubyConf organizers and are already looking to make a list of venues that could be considered if the event were to come to Kochi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby at FISAT - JIbin, a student at FISAT, proposed that we conduct a day long workshop about Ruby and Rails at his college. This will be happening on August 3. We have a separate mail thread to continue this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Year anniversary - We also celebrated the first anniversary of Ruby meetups in Kochi by cutting a cake. (Photos linked below.) The first Ruby meetup in Kochi happened in July 2012, and even though we didn&amp;#8217;t have meetups for a few months in between, we&amp;#8217;re now back to having regular monthly meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://plus.google.com/photos/102876020754850448034/albums/5901094211574087745'&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a couple of photos from the meetup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, N.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-july-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-july-2013</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meetup Minutes - 8th September, 2012</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a quick roundup of last weekend&amp;#8217;s meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vishnu Gopal from Mobme spoke about how they use Ruby at Mobme. He spoke about the non-Rails usage of Ruby and specifically spoke about two gems - sync_service and async_service that are used at Mobme for synchronous SOA daemons and daemons for processing work from queues respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akhil Stanislavose spoke about Background processing in Rails - and the delayed_job gem in particular. This was also followed by a demo of the gem and a discussion on background processing in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a discussion about how the Ruby community in Kochi could collaborate on some open source project - either a new one or an existing project. Hopefully we can have more discussion on this idea here on the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another discussion that happened was about the use of Rails for open source projects - and Projects Fedena in particular - and whether the problems in upgrading such projects from Rails 2.x to 3.x has discouraged community participation in such projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed whether we could have the next meetup in a hackathon format. That&amp;#8217;s another topic that needs discussion here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minutes prepared by &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/nithinbekal'&gt;Nithin Bekal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='presentation'&gt;Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://speakerdeck.com/vishnugopal/how-we-use-ruby-at-mobme-wireless'&gt;How we use ruby at mobme - Vishnu Gopal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-september-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-september-2012</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meetup Minutes - 5th August, 2012</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id='overview_of_august_2012_meetup'&gt;Overview of August, 2012 meetup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a great meetup this afternoon. Here&amp;#8217;s a quick summary of the meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sumit Asok spoke about Test Driven Development and gave some excellent advice on doing TDD right. Sumit explained some of the best practices when it comes to doing TDD with Rspec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Thanks Sumit for traveling all the way from Bangalore for doing this talk. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ehthisham TK spoke about Ruboto - Ruby on Android. Ruboto is a framework for developing apps using JRuby on Android. He also gave a quick demo of developing an app using the Ruboto framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the talks, the participants had discussions on various technologies. There were even some humorous and friendly diversions towards some of the classic programmer flame wars - Ruby vs Python, Rails vs Django, Sublime vs Vim vs Emacs, and editors vs IDEs. The people attending included Ruby, Python, Java and front end developers - hence the diversity in opinions. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attendance was lower compared to the last meetup, but there was plenty of enthusiastic participation from those who did attend. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue and date for future meetups was also discussed. We would love to host the event every month at WowMakers, but I agree that it would be best for the community if other Ruby shops also would get to host the meetups. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also felt that Sundays aren&amp;#8217;t the best day for meetups and Saturdays would be preferable for most people. So, for the September meetup, we&amp;#8217;ll discuss here and pick a different date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would love to hear opinions about #5 and #6. Please do reply with your thoughts. Also, if anyone&amp;#8217;s interested in doing a talk at next month&amp;#8217;s meetup, please do reply here. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minutes prepared by &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/nithinbekal'&gt;Nithin Bekal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-august-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-minutes-august-2012</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meetup - 1st July, 2012</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id='minutes_of_the_first_kerala_ruby_user_group_krug_meeting'&gt;Minutes of the First Kerala Ruby User Group (KRUG) Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harisankar presented a talk about the Cuba microframework. This was followed by Q&amp;amp;A and discussions about some of the Cuba code examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presented an intro to Ruby aimed mainly at newbies. This was followed by a general discussion about the language and the Ruby ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the people who attended were experienced with Ruby, and the talks and discussions had gone on for a while, so we didn&amp;#8217;t have the coding sessions for beginners that we had initially planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turnout at the meetup was a pleasant surprise, as there were around 18 people there. Turnout at events is usually much lower than the RSVPs, but this was just one short of the Facebook RSVPs. Hopefully we&amp;#8217;ll have even better participation for the next meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all felt that this mailing list is the best place for planning for the next meetup and proposing talks. The space at Startup Village is always available as the venue. We just need volunteers now for speaking at the next meetup. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minutes prepared by &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/nithinbekal'&gt;Nithin Bekal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.396161007098834.81084.189290137785923&amp;amp;type=1'&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-july-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krug.github.io/posts/meetup-july-2012</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>